# Yenchin Lai

Digital Media Lab, University of Bremen E-mail: ylai@uni-bremen.de

### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research during master's program is focused on human behavior, cognition, and emotion in the field of human-computer interaction. In my master's thesis, I create a face interaction system based on empirical studies. I am currently interested in affective computing and user experience. With my experience during undergraduate program, I am also interested in the related topics on interaction design for children and interactive systems for performance and art.

### **EDUCATION**

#### PhD Candidate in Computer Science

Digital Media Lab, University of Bremen, Germany Affective Computing and Experience Design

#### Master's Degree in Media Design

Graduate School of Media Design, Keio University of Japan User-Defined Face Gesture Interactions Using Webcams

#### Language Interpretation

Japan College of Foreign Languages, Tokyo, Japan

#### Bachelor's Degree in Education

Department of Human Development and Family Studies, National Taiwan Normal University

With extra-curricular credits at B.F.A Degree Program in Performing Arts

### ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

Researcher

2019-present

2019-present

2016-2018

2015-2016

2010-2014

Digital Media Lab, University of Bremen, Germany
Graduate School "Empowering Digital Media" funded by Klaus Tschira Foundation

#### Research Assistant

2018

Graduate School of Media Design, Keio University of Japan Research Assistant in Geist project

#### Teaching Assistant

2017-2018

Graduate School of Media Design, Keio University of Japan

Workshop Assistant in KMD Crash Course and Studio Assistant of Network Studio

#### Research Program Participant

2016-2017

Osaka Prefecture University of Japan

JST CREST, Research Topic: "Behavior change and harmonious collaboration by experiential supplements"

#### **Student Innovation Contest**

2016

ACM UIST 2016 Student Innovation Contest

"Most Creative Interface honorable mention" with our work "Facecook"

#### **Exchange Program**

2014

Osaka Prefecture University of Japan

An one-semester program studying in Humanities and Social Sciences and participation in seminars on the topic of Human Sexuality and Gender

### Practicum 2013

Public Zhong Xin Daycare Center, New Taipei City, Taiwan Course credits for Practicum in Early Childhood Education

### INDUSTRIAL EXPERIENCE

#### Freelance Translator and Interpreter

2012-2018

Japanese-Chinese-English Language Translation and Interpretation

Working mostly with companies and agencies related to music, entertainment, cultures, and design

#### Student Volunteer

2017

Unite 2017 Tokyo

Student volunteer for Unite 2017 Tokyo held by Unity Technologies

### Hackathon 2016-2017

Live Music Hackasong

A 3-month hackathon focusing on the idea of combining live performance and technology to create brand new live experiences held by Billboard Japan and Contents Innovation Program.

#### Game Music Design

2010-2011

"Crazy Festival" and "hielo store"

Music and sound design for Taiwanese phone games

# **PUBLICATIONS**

Lai Yen-Chin, YuanLing Feng, Kai Kunze, Junich Shimizu, and Takuro Nakao. Eyewear to Make Me Smile: Can Electric Muscle Stimulation increase Happiness? In Proceedings of the Eleventh International Conference on Tangible, Embedded, and Embodied Interaction (TEI'17). ACM, Yokohama, Japan.

George Chernyshov, Jiajun Chen, **Yenchin Lai**, Vontin Noriyasu, and Kai Kunze. Ambient Rhythm: Melodic Sonification of Status Information for IoT-enabled Devices In Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on the Internet of Things IoT'16). ACM, Stuttgart, Germany.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python, HTML, Arduino, LATEX

### LANGUAGE SKILLS

Chinese Native Speaker English Fluent, TOEIC: 815

Japanese Fluent, JLPT: N1, BJT: J1+